IBRAHIM SULEIMAN

Frontend Web Developer

+234 814 366 0104 ebeeraheem@gmail.com Rijiyar Zaki, Ungogo LGA, Kano linkedin.com/in/ebeesule/ github.com/ebeeraheem

CAREER SUMMARY:

Experienced Frontend Web Developer with a strong command of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and frontend frameworks. Skilled in crafting responsive and visually appealing web interfaces. Demonstrates a collaborative approach, with meticulous attention to detail, committed to delivering user-friendly experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

AcrossMart Ltd

Chief Operations Officer | October 2022 - December 2023

- Oversaw end-to-end operations from the company's inception to the Minimum Viable Product (MVP) launch in under 6 months.
- Played a pivotal role in the development of the e-commerce platform by optimising 30+ pages for SEO, decreasing load time by approximately 76%.
- Ensured cross-functional team efficiency and maintained seamless communication among teams throughout the project.
- Optimised 900+ images, resulting in a 435% increase in page speed.

Zenith Computer Institute

Head of Department | March 2022 - October 2022

- Managed the institution, focusing on enhancing the quality of computer education in an underserved region of Northern Nigeria.
- Led efforts to improve the educational experience for 130+ students under my supervision.
- Actively contributed to the institution's software development department, ensuring the high quality and integrity of the company's digital products, reducing 600k in development costs.

Alpha-Med Diagnostics and Clinics

Manager | September 2020 - March 2022

- Ensured the seamless operation of all departments, guaranteeing the smooth delivery of laboratory, clinical, pharmaceutical, and consultation services to clients.
- Successfully expanded Alpha-Med's service offerings to include radiology, which subsequently became the company's primary revenue source and increased revenue generation by almost 400%.

Hygrade Business Ventures

Senior Operator | January 2020 - December 2020

- Spearheaded the integration of departmental activities at Hygrade Business Ventures, streamlining processes to ensure the uninterrupted provision of services to clients which resulted in a 120% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Fostered a seamless operational environment that contributed to the consistent and superior delivery of services.

EDUCATION:

2022 - Present | Trask Global

Certificate - Software Engineering

Aug - Nov 2023 | Udacity

Nanodegree - Intro to Programming

2016 - 2022 | Kano University of Science and Technology, Wudil

Bachelor's Degree - Biology

Jan - Dec 2019 | Hygrade Business Ventures

Diploma - Computer Science

CERTIFICATIONS:

Certificate of National Service

December 2023 | NYSC

Introduction to Front End Development

November 2023 | Meta

McKinsey Forward Program

November 2023 | McKinsey & Company

Intro to Programming

October 2023 | Udacity

Entrepreneurship & Innovation

August 2023 | Forage

B.Sc (Hons) Biology

December 2022 | KUST, Wudil

SKILLS:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- Git and GitHub
- User Interface Design

- MS Office Suite
- Adobe Creative Suite
- CorelDRAW
- WordPress
- Wix
- Mobile-first Development Practices
- Accessibility standards

- · Agile Methodologies
- Communication
- Independence and Collaboration
- Leadership and Teamwork
- Attention to Detail
- Responsive Design
- Cross Browser Compatibility
- Web Performance Optimization